Jeffrey Johnson

Albuquerque, NM

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/leffrey-Johnson/9df255f227c13aed

Electrical Engineer | Radio Frequency (RF)

20+ years of experience researching and developing RF and Analog hardware in digital communication systems and RFID. Perform complex analysis using software tools for circuit and system design. Perform component evaluation, selection, and documentation. Schematic capture and layout of PCBs. Design Verification

Testing, prototyping and integrating at system level. Document and transition designs to manufacturing group, RMA support over product life cycle. Author test procedures, product specifications, and technical Engineering documents. Work well with different groups in the organization by effectively communicating and responding timely to their needs.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

RF Engineer III

TransCore - Albuquerque, NM June 2016 to April 2021

RF/Microwave /Analog circuit design of RFID systems. Built and tested prototypes.

Technical Lead on various multi-protocol readers as well as active and passive tags. Optimized Tag antennas

Major Projects: Compact Reader for Railway Asset Tracking, Tags for railway and other vehicles. 900 MHz Crystal Oscillator

Ceramic Filter Designer

CTS Electronic Components - Albuquerque, NM April 2014 to April 2016

Designed, tuned and prepared ceramic monoblock filter evaluation samples for customers in military, space, and commercial markets

Major Projects: Space-gualified Diplexer, Miniature Narrowband Bandpass Filters

RF Engineer

L-3 Communications June 1998 to April 2013

RF circuit design: LNAs, PAs, PLLs, Phase Shifters, Oscillators, Discreet Filters Major Projects: Antenna Pointing control module, Multi-Band Frequency Converters, AGC loops

Education

M.S. in Electrical Engineering

University of Utah - Salt Lake City, UT

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Electrical Engineering University of Utah - Salt Lake City, UT September 1993 to May 1997

Skills

- Technical Skills
- Technically leading a product from Design to Production
- RF/Microwave Circuit Design 10 MHz to 18 GHz
- Schematic development and Capture
- Layout for RF/Digital PCBs
- Troubleshooting and resolving manufacturing issues
- RFID Reader and Tag designs
- PLL Synthesizer Simulation and Design
- Testing e.g. vibration, temperature
- RF Transceiver Cascade Analysis
- Electromagnetic and Circuit simulation: Microwave Office, ADS, HFSS, LTSpice
- Rapid Prototyping
- LKPF milling machine
- Some Antenna Design: Patch, Microstrip
- Radio System Architecture Planning
- MATLAB, some VBA for Excel
- FCC certification. Qualification/Safety testing,
- Soldering, building and testing prototypes
- Data Analysis/Visualization
- Statistics